终空
前情提要
【家长提示】本片的评级为 TV-14-DLV，
可能包含暗示性对话、粗俗语言和暴力等内容，
因而不建议 14 岁以下儿童独自观赏。
在一艘监狱飞船上独自一人度过了五年的刑期后
After five years of jail time alone on a prison ship,
我们的英雄盖瑞结交了一个  不  是两个朋友
our hero Gary made not one, but two friends.
其中一个是行星杀手  另一个则是危险的赏金猎人
One is a planet-killer, the other a deadly bounty hunter.
而这两个朋友都与一个大混蛋“总司令”有所关联
And both of them lead right back to the Lord Commander, who's kind of a jerk-face.
不过  真正的重点是
Well, guess what?!
我们即将迎来一个伟大的开始
We're off to a great start,
所以“坐”好准备  因为接下来的剧情要爆炸了
so buckle up those butt cheeks, 'cause things are about to get heavy.
盖瑞  你的氧气还够用8分钟
Gary, you have eight minutes of oxygen left.
HUE  如果你还有8分钟的生命
HUE, if you had eight minutes to live
随便你做什么都行
and you could do anything you wanted,
你会选择做什么？
what would you do?
演算中
Facticulating.
Ahh.
我会把我的人工智能转化为有形的存在
I would transfer my A.I. into a corporeal being
然后去巴黎看看
and go see Paris.
这也太俗了吧
Oh, that's lame!
我是说  天啊  很棒…真的
I mean, wow. Super... cool.
你会选择做什么  盖瑞？
What would you do, Gary?
做什么都行
Absolutely anything.
只要能跟奎恩在一起
And I mean anything with Quinn.
说真的  就算是看《星河驱动》都行
I mean, we could watch "Space Drive" for all I care.
对于这样的结果  我表示遗憾
I'm sorry things turned out this way.
世事难料啊
Crap happens.
Translated by @SerCom_KC
OPEN TRANSLATION PROJECT
拉克斯星团     432G区
Translated by @SerCom_KC
OPEN TRANSLATION PROJECT
♪ 洞  洞  洞  洞  盖上洞洞 ♪
♪ Holes, holes, holes, holes, cover up these holes ♪
翻译版本
v1.0.0-CHS
♪ 塞洞洞 ♪
♪ Plug these holes ♪
翻译
SerCom_KC
♪ 洞  洞  洞 ♪
♪ Holes, holes, holes ♪
♪ 修个洞洞  修个洞洞 ♪
♪ Nothing but holes, nothing but holes ♪
校对
旗木佐罗
♪ 修个洞洞  洞洞  洞洞 ♪
♪ Nothing but holes, but holes, but holes ♪
♪ 洞  洞  洞  盖上洞洞 ♪
♪ Holes, holes, holes, cover up these holes ♪
校对
万俟猫
♪ 塞洞洞  洞  洞 ♪
♪ Plug these holes, holes, holes ♪
♪ 修个洞洞 ♪
♪ Nothing but holes ♪
♪ 洞  洞  洞 ♪
♪ Holes, holes, holes ♪
♪ 洞洞 ♪
♪ But holes ♪
时间轴
SerCom_KC
♪  塞洞…塞 ♪
♪ Plug these -- plug ♪
♪ 塞洞洞呀洞 ♪
♪ Plug these holes and holes ♪
特效
SerCom_KC
♪ 洞洞洞  洞 ♪
♪ Holes, holes, holes, holes ♪
奎恩  是我  盖瑞
Quinn, it's me, Gary.
我这边一切顺利
Things have been great on my end.
交了个我认为迟早会成为新朋友的人
I made what I believe to be a potential new friend.
没错  虽然他登船是为了杀我
Yes, he boarded the ship to kill me
然后带走我的小绿球朋友
and take my little green ball friend,
但阿瓦卡多真的打得一手好牌
but Avocato is one great card player.
再让我打牌我就开枪自杀
Any more cards and I will shoot myself.
你要是不打牌我就开枪杀了你
I'm gonna shoot you if you don't play cards.
来啊  随你开
I'll let you shoot me.
呃  哦  真…
Um, oh -- real--
既然这样  那我就开枪自杀
Well, then I'm gonna shoot myself!
什么？为啥啊？
What? Why?
随你他妈的想去吧  慢慢想
Frickin' figure it out. Figure it out.
而我们的新成员就是这个小家伙！
And our newest member is this little guy!
他叫月饼
His name's Mooncake.
Ooh-wow!
大家都很喜欢他
Everyone loves him.
翻译项目地址
translatedby.sercomkc.org/finalspace
那个绿色的小鼻涕球
That little green snot-ball
可是能毁灭行星的超级武器
is a planet-destroying super-weapon
我们迟早会因它而死
that's gonna get us killed.
本翻译作品按照CC BY-NC-SA 4.0许可协议向公众授权
未经授权禁止用于任何商业用途
这位先生  你这句话就很过分了
You, sir, just stepped over the line.
月饼是懂感情的
Mooncake has feelings.
却被你一泡猫尿浇到伤透
And you just peed all over them with your cat whiz.
没错  我这边真的很顺利
Yep. Things have been going pretty great.
记得回复我  不用太赶喔
Get back to me. No rush.
只是  我有差不多五年的时间没跟一个人类女性聊过了
It's just I haven't talked to a human lady person in, like, five years.
永远爱你喔  闪电强盗
Well, yours forever. Thunder bandit!
消息发送
Message sent.
地球
没错  我就是撩妹高手
I crushed it... again!
我是奎恩
Quinn.
你好  奎恩  我是三烦
Hey, Quinn, it's Tribore.
一艘无疆守护的飞船坠毁了
An Infinity Guard ship has crashed.
到底是如何坠毁的  没人知道
How did it crash, we don't know.
快点来现场
We need you on the scene.
马上就来
On my way.
Ha.
妈妈咪啊  我的天啊
Oh, mama. Oh, boy.
Oh!
检测到未经许可的扫描行为
Unauthorized scan detected.
你好呀  盖瑞？
What ya doing, Gary?
找到了  “总司令”…
Gotcha. Lord Commander --
Agh!
Hmm.
设置坐标至“兆压”
Set course for Tera Con Prime.
这又是啥鬼？
What the heck is this thing?
凡特克西隐形探针  一定是特克
A Ventrexian stealth probe -- Terk.
我就知道是特克
Of course, Terk.
特克又他妈是谁？
Who the hell is Terk?
他跟我一样是赏金猎人
A bounty hunter -- like me.
既然他发现了月饼
Well, if he scanned Mooncake,
他肯定会去“总司令”那里请求增援
he'll be on his way back to the Lord Commander to gather reinforcements.
Mm-hmm.
所以我们一定要阻止他
Unless we stop him first.
Mm-hmm.
否则  他们就会抓走月饼
If we don't, they will capture Mooncake.
Mnh-mnh.
然后把我们带到暗域
And take us to the Dark Zone.
Mnh-mnh.
用扎尔贡的蛞蝓折磨我们
And torture us with Zargon Slugs.
Mnh-mnh.
我们将永远活在痛苦与创伤中
Or we're gonna suffer pain and anguish for eternity.
Oh.
让它们停下来的唯一方式是撒盐
And the only way to stop them is with salt.
Oh.
但是  在暗域里  是没有盐的
And there's no salt in the Dark Zone.
Hmm.
你这么一说还真是危在旦夕了啊
Sounds like I got these buttery buns into a hot vise.
我要怎么阻止他们？
How do I stop them?
你一个人是做不到的
You don't.
不过  我们两个人联手也许会有机会
But together, we've got a shot.
给我松绑  我们一起去追他
Get me out of these cuffs, and we'll go after him.
哇哇哇哇哇  牛仔先生
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, cowboy!
你刚才还准备杀了我呢
You tried to kill me.
想让我相信你的话  先来握个手
If you want me to trust you, first we clasp.
我才不来呢
I'm not doing that.
得了吧  你肯定要握手的
Oh, yes, you will. You will do that.
我们刚刚愉快地打了牌
We've enjoyed recreational cards together.
接下来当然要握手啦
This is the next step.
只要手拉手  就能铸造出完美的信任
A hand-to-hand bond that forges the completion of a newfound trust.
该不会还要脱到全裸  坦诚相待吧？
We don't have to get balls to the wind naked, do we?
按照传统  这是必须的  不过算你走运
Tradition demands yes. But you're lucky.
我这人的思想还是比较进步的
I'm more of a progressive.
进入信任模式
Trust mode engaged.
我已经有五年的时间没离开过这艘飞船了
It's been five years since I've been off this ship!
我超期待冒险
I am pumped for adventure!
一起去抓住这个家伙吧
Let's get this guy!
HUE  把气闸打开
HUE, open the airlock.
你还是一名囚犯  谁知道你会不会逃跑呢？
You are a prisoner. How will I know you won't run?
我还能去哪…
I got nowhere to g--
注射
Inject.
啊！这他妈又搞啥？
Ow! What the freak was that?!
如果五个小时内你没有回到飞船上
If you are not back aboard this ship in five hours,
你的大脑将会发生痉挛  随后爆炸
your brain will go into convulsive spasms and then explode.
冲啊
Let's go!
不带上月饼去吗？
Shouldn't we take Mooncake?
太危险了  赶紧赶紧
It's too dangerous. Make haste, make haste!
我会想你的  伙计  要乖哦
I'll miss you, bud. Be good.
还有别尿到我东西上了
And don't whiz on any of my stuff.
兆压     18650区
噢  噢  有烧烤
Oh, oh! Street meat!
他们这里有烧烤卖  阿瓦卡多
They got street meat, Avocato!
专心
Focus.
好的  我很专心
Okay, I'm focused.
好的  我们要抓住特克
All right, we're getting Terk.
一切为了星系  一切为了永恒  一切为了“总司令”
For the galaxy, for eternity, for Lord Commander.
能平安到达这里算你幸运
You're lucky that we even made it here.
他们对智人很是反感
They don't take kindly to Homo sapiens.
现在我们去24层帮你搞一张证件
Now let's go to tier 24 and get you identification papers.
哈  我才不需要什么证件
Ha! I don't need papers.
不然他们就会把你液化
Or they'll liquify you.
你刚才是不是说了液化？还是说我大脑开始痉挛了？
Did you just say liquify? Or was that a brain spasm?
是…是在痉挛吗？
It... is it happening?
我的妈  真的痉挛了
Oh, my crap, it's happening.
否则  杀无赦
Or we'll kill you.
盖瑞  跟紧一点
Gary, stay close.
好  别担心  我不会乱走的
Right, don't worry. I'm not going anywhere.
盖瑞！
Gary!
吃点烧烤嘛
Getting some street meat!
出示证件！
Identification papers!
呃  我好像是放在了  嗯…
Um, I must have left them in, um...
这里有个偷渡的
We got a runner.
我们还是去弄证件吧
Maybe we should get some papers.
Mm-hmm.
欢迎来到飞机舱
Welcome to the hangar bay!
不过我喜欢把它叫做虎穴
But I call it the tiger's nest.
你肯定想问为什么
And I bet you're wondering why.
那么好吧  我就告诉你
Well, okay, I'll tell you.
Whoo!
呃  请问有什么可以帮您？
Uh, excuse me, can I help you?
呃  你好
Uh, hello.
快跑啊！快跑啊！
Run away! Run away!
啊  阿瓦卡多  真是好久不见
Ahh. Avocato, it's so good to see you.
是什么风把你吹到我的一元小店了？
What brings you to my little shop of doo-dads?
废话少说  克莱伦斯
Cut the crap, Clarence!
没错  废话少说  克莱伦斯
Yeah, cut the crap, Clarence.
我们需要证件
We need papers.
没错  证件
That's right, papers.
这个嘛  证件可不是便宜货
Well, papers are not cheap.
Oh!
你的小命不也一样  何况你还是我救下来的
Neither is your life, and I saved that.
是的  没错  你是救了我
Yes, right, I suppose you did.
但这真的是最后一次了
But this is the last time.
你的证件好弄
Your papers are easy.
但这只灵长目
But this primate...
Hey!
就不太好弄了
... is gonna be much more difficult.
别用你的手指戳我肚皮
Get your finger out of my tummy.
喔  还会说话啊
Ooh! It speaks.
你倒是挺会训练东西的
I guess you can train anything.
我想怎么戳就怎么戳  你个灵长目！
I'll touch you any time I wish, primate!
Hmm.
嗯  不对  不是这个  稍等一下
Yes, no, not that one. Hold on a second.
应该就放在这下面
Down here at the bottom, possibly.
啊  没错  就是这个
Oh, yes, here we go.
胡博拉特人的尸皮
Skin of a dead Hooblat.
我要穿上这东西？
I have to get in this thing?
简直就像一个超滑的皮塔饼
It's like a slippery Pita pocket.
你想被液化  然后看着月饼和银河一号被摧毁吗？
You want to be liquefied and have Mooncake and the Galaxy One destroyed?
不想  你…你是怎么知道的？
No, h-- how the hell do you know that?
早就传遍了  大家都在讨论这个
It's everywhere. It's all anyone's talking about.
Huh.
赶紧套上去！
Get in the skin!
为了月饼我拼了
For Mooncake.
我的妈呀  居然还是温的
Oh, my God, it's so warm!
我…还是湿的！
Oh, it's -- and wet!
噢  真…其实还挺  算舒服的
Oh. It... actually kind of feels kind of nice,
就像一对又温暖又有点湿的拖鞋
like a pair of warm, wet house slippers.
这完全没道理啊
It doesn't make any sense.
是啊  这完全没道理啊
I know. It doesn't make any sense.
要是有道理就好了
I wish there was sense.
道理都到哪里去了呢？
Where did all the sense go?
搞不懂  这可是绝统T3
I don't get it. It's an Imperium T3.
这种机型不应该坠毁才对
These things don't crash.
它们不会坠毁  你说得对
They don't crash, you're right.
这完全没道理啊
It doesn't make any sense.
为啥它会坠毁呢？
Why would it crash?
三烦  看着我的眼睛
Tribore, look me in the eye.
然后请你闭嘴
Now shut up.
我应该闭嘴
I should shut up.
为啥我还在说话呢？
Why do I keep talking?
你看到这个读数了吗？
Are you reading this?
万有引力常数出现了偏差
The gravitational constant is shifting.
我有在看  我有啊
I am seeing it. I am!
如此强烈的干扰真的会让整个宇宙撕裂的
A disturbance this strong can literally tear the universe apart.
入侵者警告
Intruder alert.
启动反重力对抗措施
Initiating anti-gravity countermeasures.
机器人  启动防御程序
SAMES, initiate defense sequence.
S A M E S
总之  我还是要负责这里的安全的
Anyway, I'm kind of in charge of security around here,
所以我有一个大请求
which brings me to a big ask.
你能出去帮我拿一片饼干吗？
Could you go out there and get me a cookie?
Chookity.
太好了
Score!
好吧  那我就留在这里守要塞了
All right, I'll stay here and guard the fort.
…你会死的
[... you're gonna die!]
我就说吧
Told ya!
我看上去怎样  讲实话
How do I look? Be honest.
给你打个2分吧
I'd give you a 2.
才2分？
Just a 2?
我觉得我还是再去弄弄头发吧
Get my hair done or something, you know.
我选择拒绝
How about no?
不是  讲真  我可以去做高光
No, seriously, I could get highlights.
你看  我可以去染个渐层
I could get ombre hair, you know?
真是难以置信
I can't believe it.
相信我  我一定要弄个渐层染发
Believe it, because this ombre hair is happening.
不是  特克啊！
No. Terk!
我的妈  真的是特克
Oh, crap, it is Terk.
看什么看？看什么看？
What are you looking at? What are you looking at?
走了
Let's go.
Hmm.
自以为能逃得出我们手心是吧？
Thought you could rat us out, huh?
你他妈是谁  老东西？
Who the hell are you, you old bag?
好吧  你这句太伤人了
Okay. That just hurts.
阿瓦卡多！
Avocato!
不！
No!
你这家伙  把我丢在船上听天由命
Give me one reason I don't kill you right now
给我一个不能杀你的理由！
for leaving me to die on that ship!
我知道你的儿子在哪里
Because I know where your son is.
我的儿子？
My son?
在哪里？他在哪里？
Where? Where is he?
第43号拘留房
Holding cell 43.
他…他在这里？
He's... he's here?
放我走
Now let me go.
好  我放你走
I'll let you go.
走去地狱吧
I'll let you go to Hell.
我来了  小卡多
I'm coming, Little Cato.
梅勒妮·德温特  等级4
Melanie Dewinter, level 4.
梅勒妮·德…什…什么？
Melanie De-- wh-- what?!
Aah!
Oh!
妈妈！
Mommy!
你回来啦
You're back!
回来了喔
I sure am!
不要啊
Oh, no!
梅勒妮！
Melanie!
噢  他们还说你死了呢！
Oh, they told us you were dead!
Oh!
我跟你妹的事情都是误会啊
Everything with your sister was a mistake.
哎  呀  妈
Oh, my crap.
坐好
Sit tight.
我听不见
I can't hear you.
我搞砸了  全都搞砸了
I messed up. I messed up bad!
但无论付出多大的代价  我保证
But I'm not gonna leave you here. I promise.
我绝不会把你丢在这里的
I'll do whatever it takes.
不要啊  爸爸！
No, dad!
爸爸  快跑！有埋伏！
Dad, run! It's a trap!
爸爸  小心！
Dad, watch out!
爸  爸  爸  不要啊！
Dad, dad, dad, no!
把他带到“总司令”那里去
Take him to the Lord Commander.
我更爱妈妈
I love Mommy more!
不  我更爱妈妈！
No, I love Mommy more!
好吧  能不能  呃  别…这样…
Okay, just, uh -- stop -- keep --
别拉太用力  宝贝们
stop tugging too hard, babies.
梅勒妮？
Melanie?!
天啊
Oh, God!
你们…大概有问题要问吧
So... you probably have a few questions.
给我出去  你个疯子！
Get out of here, you maniac!
Hyah!
Huh!
阿瓦卡多！
Avocato!
Whew.
一日握手终日为友
The clasp of friends.
再过两小时我就会脑浆飞溅
Only two hours till my brain shoots out of my eyes.
动作要快点了
I gotta move fast.
地球
长官  紧急状况
Sir, there's an emergency.
我们必须马上让所有的无疆守护巡航船返回地面
We need to ground all Infinity Guard cruisers immediately.
什么  你又来这套  奎恩
What?! Not again, Quinn.
一场全宇宙的浩劫就要发生了
There's a cosmic disaster taking place.
我们必须要找出这背后的…
We need to find out what's causing --
奎恩  住口
Quinn, shut up!
绝统T3坠毁是因为人为失误
The Imperium T3 crashed because of human error.
是吗？跟证据讲你的鬼话去吧
Yeah? Tell that to science.
真的是蠢
You're an idiot.
请支持我  队长
Back me up, Captain.
请你离开  奎恩
Time to leave, Quinn.
好吧  队长也是个笨蛋
Okay. The Captain is also an idiot.
中尉？
Lieutenant?
你们全都是笨蛋
You're all idiots!
笨蛋  笨蛋
Idiots, idiots!
你们是笨蛋吗？为啥你们都会是笨蛋？
Are you idiots? Why would you all be idiots?
我觉得你们都很聪明啊
I think you're all very smart.
那我还是溜了吧
Well, I gotta go.
请立即停止  请立即停止  否则我将采取…
Stop! Stop, or I will be forced to...
启发式统一实体
运行中
状态
入侵者警告 - 机器人（SAMES）已派遣
光折引擎正常
手动操作模式  禁用HUE…
Manual override of A.I. HUE disable...
阿瓦卡多
Avocato.
我们有约在先
We had a deal.
你承诺过要把E-351带给我
You promised me E-351
结果你失败了  又失败了
and you failed... again.
请相信我  我一定做得到
Trust me, I can do this.
我已经很接近了
I'm close.
喔  噢  好棒啊
Ooh! Ooh, hurray.
那我什么时候才能拿到呢？
When will it be mine?
等等  你该不会把它藏在身上了吧？
Wait, are you hiding it on you?
你在玩游戏吗  我最喜欢游戏了
Is this a game? I love games.
它不在我手上
I don't have it.
但我可以把那个拥有它的人交给你
But I can get you the man who does.
他的名字是盖瑞
His name is Gary.
我把他交给你  你把我的儿子还来
I get you him, you give me back my son.
没得谈
No deal.
原来你在这里啊
There you are!
天啊  今天过得真是刺激
What a day I've had, man.
我…我好像把一个家庭毁了
I... I think I destroyed a family.
那真是…我们现在能走了吗？
Oh. So how about we get out of here?
想必你就是“那个”盖瑞吧
You must be the Gary.
好吧  其实  我就叫盖瑞
Okay. Actually, it's just Gary.
“那个”盖瑞
The Gary.
就叫盖瑞
Just Gary.
就是  就…就…没有…
You know, just -- just -- there's no...
为啥要加“那个”？
Where's this "the" coming from?
好吧  今天是玩开心了  但…
Well, this has been great. But...
阿瓦卡多  快逃！
Avocato, run!
我还没做自我介绍呢
I haven't introduced myself.
我就是“总司令”
I am the Lord Commander.
哦  原来就是你啊  好棒喔
Oh, is that you? That's fantastic.
但我们真的要…阿瓦卡多！
But we really gotta -- Avocato!
你的手上有我的东西  所以我现在要要回来
You have something of mine, and I want it.
过来吧  “那个”盖瑞
Come here, the Gary.
发生了什么？天啊
What is going on? Oh, God!
好吧  这就…被需要是不错
Okay, this is -- it's nice to be wanted.
通   缉
但这…这要的有点多了吧
But this is -- this is too much want.
你到底是想乖乖把E-351给我
Are you going to give me E-351,
还是想让我慢慢给你断肢？
or should I tear you limb from limb?
阿瓦卡多  帮个忙啊
Avocato, a little help.
Oh! Oh!
阿瓦卡多  一日握手终日为友啊
Avocato, the clasp of friends!
求你了  兄弟  阿瓦卡多！
Please, man! Avocato!
开启…友情模式！
Friend mode! Engaged!
友情？
Friend?
他可是背叛了你喔
He was just betraying you.
不对  我们握了手
Untrue. We clasped hands.
对吧  兄弟？
Right, bro?
其实我绝望了  老兄
I was desperate, man.
我只想救我的儿子
I was trying to save my son.
Aah!
妈妈咪啊
Oh, my God!
我操你有病啊  那他妈是我手臂啊！
You idiot! That's my freakin' arm!
就这么给你硬生生扯下来了啊！
You just ripped the thing off!
Aah!
我的天啊  妈个鸡搞啥
Oh, my God! Oh, what the freak?!
我的血要喷没了啊！
I'm spraying all my blood!
我要把你的脸扒下来
I am going to murder your face off!
我会把你的脸扒上去
I will murder your face on!
你这话根本就说不通！
That doesn't make any sense!
快逃
Run!
Oh!
走了
Come on!
给我追
After them!
噢  好多台阶啊
Oh, there's so many stairs!
不要说话了  白痴
Quit talking, you idiot!
搞不懂为啥那么多台阶啊
I don't know, why are there so many stairs?!
盖瑞  我不能丢下我儿子不管
Gary, I can't leave my son.
好好好  我跟你去
Oh, we're going, all right --
不过快点  我脑袋要爆炸了
and fast -- before my brain explodes!
我们没法回运输机了
We're not gonna make it back to the transporter.
看来我们可以开别的
Looks like we got a new ride.
好吧  不太理想  但起码能开
Okay, not ideal, but still a ride.
喂喂喂！
Oh, come on!
我都不知道这是啥
I don't even know what that is.
妈卖批
Crap it hard!
我们跳到架空走道上去
We jump to the catwalk.
猫      行      道
你是疯子吗？
Are you insane?
不对  我是大疯子
No, I'm super insane.
Ha ha ha!
我的妈
Oh my god!
漂亮  小子们
Attaboys.
记得把皮留给我哦
I'll need that suit back.
我们要掉下去了  妈呀
We're falling! Oh, my gosh!
Wahhh!
我的天啊  大卫  孩子们
Oh, my God, David, kids!
是我  妈妈来了
It's me, your mother!
不  我的手臂啊
No, my arm!
我把我手臂丢上面了啊
I forgot my arm back up there!
这下糟了
This is no good!
HUE  接应  接应啊！
HUE, pick up, pick up!
那两个不会真的是那啥吧？
Are those what I think they are?
毒蛇炮塔
Viper turrets.
好吧  这下糟了  真的糟了
Okay, that's not good. That's not good!
快点  抱我
Quick, hug me.
抱你？
Hug you?
朋友抱
Hug a friend!
什么？
What?!
快点抱我
Hug me!
喔  我们抱在一起了
Oh, we're hugging!
护
盾
HUE？HUE  请求连线
HUE? HUE, come in!
奎恩
Quinn.
奎恩  你要去哪？
Quinn, where are you going?
去抢一架飞鹰
To the first Hawk I can jack.
马上就有大事要发生
Something big is happening,
不能指望指挥部里那帮袖手旁观的人
and I'm not waiting while command sits around,
个个闲到玩丁丁
twiddling their wieners.
也许我无法阻止这一切
Maybe I can't stop it,
但我一定要查明真相
but I'm going to find out what it is.
掩护我
Cover for me.
为啥他们要玩丁丁？
Why would they be twiddling their wieners?
为啥啊？
Why?
等等  我要六片饼干
Wait, I'm gonna need six cookies.
再要一片  所以是七…八片饼干
And another one. So seven -- eight cookies.
等等  九片饼干
Wait, nine cookies!
算了  还是去帮他一下吧
Ah, I guess I better give him a hand.
手动操作
模式
KVN  终有一天  要靠你来拯救银河一号
KVN, you're going to have to save the Galaxy One someday.
手动操作
模式
答案已经进入你的机体
Inside of you now is the answer.
嘿  月饼  我是夜幕
Hey, Mooncake. My name is Nightfall.
决不可让盖瑞因你而死
Don't let Gary die because of you.
启发式统一实体
恢复上线
状态
冷却 - 机器人（SAMES）冷却
光折引擎依然很正常
HUE  请求连线  HUE！
HUE! Come in, HUE!
Arrr--
什么事  盖瑞？
Yes, Gary?
搞什么  HUE？
What the crap, HUE?!
我呼叫你好久了
I've been calling you.
赶紧捞我们走  立刻马上！
We need you to scoop us up A.S.A.P.P.!
马上就来  盖瑞
On my way, Gary.
嘿  盖瑞  你的手臂没了欸
He-e-e-ey, Gary, your arm is gone.
我的天  是吗？真的吗？
Oh, my gosh. Is it? Really?
我知道我手臂没了
I know my arm is gone,
你这坨烂翔
you decaying pile of fecal matter!
快点把我脑袋里的东西弄出来  HUE
Now get this thing out of my head, HUE.
噢  其实它根本就不会爆炸  盖瑞
Oh. It was never going to explode, Gary.
这只是我的幽默感而已
That's just my sense of humor.
你花了五年的时间编一个玩笑
You make one joke in five years,
结果就编出这么个玩意儿？
and that is the one you tell?
守时  是最重要的  盖瑞
Timing... is everything, Gary.
Hmm.
Whoo.
我的手臂  我的手臂啊
My arm! My arm!
有意思
Interesting.
通过手术为你移植一个机械臂确实是可行的
We can surgically implant an animatronic arm on you.
盖瑞  你不在的时候  有个入侵者…
Gary, while you were gone, an intruder --
把你插槽闭上  KVN
Shut your face hole, KVN.
没听到刚才说啥吗？我要换机械臂了
Didn't you just hear the news? I'm getting a robot arm.
但需要有人来完成这一过程  盖瑞
But someone will need to perform the procedure, Gary.
我来吧
I'll do it.
你？
You?
构造临时动脉分流
Create temporary arterial shunt.
我感觉我们能成为超级要好的朋友  老兄
I thought we were gonna be like super friends, man.
过去三年来  我所做的只有一件事  盖瑞
I've had one mission for the past three years, Gary,
就是找到我的儿子
and that is to find my son.
你应该早点告诉我的  我们可是握手为友了啊
You should have told me. We did the clasp of friends.
我肯定会直说要一起带你的儿子回来
I would have straight-up helped you get your son back.
什么？为什么？我根本就是个陌生人
What? Why? You barely know me.
哟  我们可是一起打了九个小时的牌
Yo, we played nine hours of cards together.
这对于你来说也许没什么  但于我是很有意义的
That might not mean something to you, but it did to me.
暴露骨骼以便电镀
Expose bone for plating.
朋友之间越走越近
Friends help each other through thick
到了亲密无间的时候  自然就会互相帮助了
and thin and thinner and nothing.
我…我没有什么可以回馈你的
I -- I have nothing to give in return.
不  你有
Yeah, you do, yo.
你的友谊就是回馈
Your friendship, yo.
我一直被关在这里  身边全都是机器人
I've been stuck here for so long with just freakin' robots.
你瞧
Look!
机器人
Robot!
他妈的机器人
Freakin' robot.
另一个贝丝
那个是冰箱  盖瑞
That's the refrigerator, Gary.
是嘛  我可是很认真地跟那家伙谈过黑暗的话题
Really? Because I've had some serious, dark conversations with that thing.
它知道我的一切
It knows everything about me.
另一个贝丝
给我保持安静  你个满嘴胡言的机器人
Keep your mouth shut, you lying robot!
微血管移植覆盖完成
Micro-vascular transplant coverage complete.
虽然这样建立友谊的方式很不传统  但…
It's an unconventional way to start a friendship, but --
Hmm?
Shh!
不要说话  握手
No words. Only clasps.
兄弟  这次你是认真的？
Bro, you being real this time?
绝对认真  小子
As real as it gets, baby.
那我向你保证  我们一定会把你的儿子带回来
Then I promise you, we will get your son back.
而且保证月饼的安全
And keep Mooncake safe.
还要把那家伙的脸扒下来
And murder that guy's face off.
那个还是算了吧
I don't think that's a great idea.
绝对真实的友谊模式开启
Real raw friendship mode engaged.
Ooh!
送你去一个你的父亲永远都找不到的地方吧
Where you're going, your father will never find you.